# Jay D

Gmail: dungavathjayanth Linkedin: jayanthdeejay Github: jayanthdeejay

# Summary

I have been a jack of all trades, master of none, for most of my life, except for core competencies. Never worked on similar tech for more than three years in a row. Enthusiastic to learn and work on tech that I had never worked on before.

Spent the last couple of years studying blockchain technologies ground up from consensus mechanisms to cryptographic algorithms, blockchains' evolution, underlying tech-stack, distributed Defi applications, etc. Before that, worked as a Ruby on Rails Full-Stack Development engineer as well as a DevOps Engineer. Saved over a quarter-million dollars a year in licensing and infrastructure costs by going for a fully open-source tech stack and research computing infrastructure.

For my master's thesis, worked on a dynamic dial-a-ride implementation at UC and suggested solutions that theoretically reduced wait times and overall performance improvement by 30%. Before joining UC, I worked at an international bank's primary data center as an IT Manager, as well as a Systems Engineer at an IT services company in India.

#### Skills

• Programming, Data Structures, Algorithms, Python, Scripting, PL/SQL, Linux, Unix, Security, Project Management, System Design, BFS learner

# Experience

Founder

Swades Coin Ltd.

May 2021 - Present

Hyderabad, India

 Working on building an application that provides cryptocurrency data insights and explorer API services.

#### Full Stack Engineer

WPI

Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

Worcester, MA

- Gathering requirements, planning, system design, document, and build scalable digital repository web applications using Ruby on Rails framework and Samvera Hyrax engine to publish digital scholarship in a start-up like environment.
- SSO with Microsoft Azure, Python ingestion tool, Ansible configuration management including application and system security, and application deployment with CI/CD pipelines.
- Mentored junior developer and practiced agile development methodologies on Jira and oversaw the software development life cycle.

### Software Developer Intern

**UC** Libraries

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

Cincinnati, OH

- Back-end developer in Ruby on Rails, Perl and other scripting languages to design, develop and document https://scholar.uc.edu/.
- Came up with an elegant no-code solution to make application data read-only after analyzing application data pipelines.
- Automated information retrieval and integrity checks during migration with Perl/Shell scripting.

Cincinnati, OH

- Assisted Dr. Fred Annexstein in teaching Intro., to Computer Science with Python and oversaw labs, grading & feedback.
- Built a JavaScript/Bootstrap UI web application with basic HTML5 and CSS to showcase digital collections and repositories using Isotope library. https://goo.gl/nX562G.
- Wrote scripts to automate data processing and management, and saved months of manual work down to overnight scheduled jobs.

# IT Manager II

Oriental Bank of Commerce

Aug 2013 - Jun 2014

Navi Mumbai, India

• Worked at an international bank's high volume production Data Center as an IT manager and oversaw data center operations management, networking and storage solutions.

#### System Engineer

**Tata Consultancy Services** 

Aug 2010 - Mar 2013

Hyderabad, India

- SAP Basis, Oracle, IBM DB2 database administration and incident management.
- Administered SAP applications, 4 production and 16 non-production UNIX/Linux servers running on a cluster environment.

#### Education

Cincinnati, OH

University of Cincinnati

Aug 2014 | Apr 2018

• MS in Computer Science.

Anantapur, India

JNTU Anantapur

Aug 2006 | May 2010

• BTech in Computer Science and Engineering.

#### Awards

- Pratibha Award (AP State Chief Minister) District topper in 11 + 12th grade 2006
- On The Spot (Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.) On The Spot Award for being a quick and continuous learner. May 2012
- Graduate Incentive Award (University of Cincinnati) Graduate Scholarship Aug 2014